depending on the person's needs besides
healthy diet and exercise what are
supplemental vitamins minerals or
peptides you would recommend while on
trt that would hurt to
add so every man woman and child in
America seems to be vitamin D3
deficient uh so I do recommend at least
5,000 I use of vitamin D3 per day uh it
is a one of our for fat soluble vitamins
so you do want to consume it with a
fatty meal you can have eggs in the
morning or anything of the sort so it
absorbs better for those that are not
contraindicated to vitamin K2 if you're
not in a blood thinner like like warrin
for example um then you should take your
D3 with 200 micrograms of K2 combined it
does help absorption as well and helps
to keep the calcium out of your blood in
in your bones um so so we have our D we
have our k um any nitric oxide booster
I'm a big fan of el citrine uh you
couple that up with tadalfil again as as
long as you're not hypotensive or taking
any anti hypertensive uh
anti-hypertensive drugs um El citrine
I'm a big fan you know I use about three
grams a day myself vitamin C two to
three grams a day I'm a fan of vitamin A
10,000 I use a day these are all Basics
and these are the type of of of
nutrients that you really are not going
to get sufficient levels of in a
multivitamin multivitamins are great but
they kind of help to make you know
expensive urine they don't really absorb
very well because they try to pack too
much into too little and
you know unless you're taking you know
multivitamin where serving size is like
four or five capsules it's very
difficult to take a one a day and expect
to get everything you need uh if you
look at the nutritional list on them the
rdas or the recommended daily allowances
a lot of those were designed back in the
1950s and they are not applicable today
to the way we live and and and our needs
and our deficiencies because back then
deficiencies were not as prevalent as
they are now quality of food was
different the level of activity and
exercise was different with modern
technology we're a very seditary Society
uh our food contains very very little or
to no nutrients whatsoever so we don't
eat the same way okay there was no you
know Chick-fil-A drive-through back then
and people used to actually eat garden
fresh fruit and animals and the
deficiencies that we encounter today do
require um higher levels of nutrients so
multivitamins kind of flawed uh but
again vitamin C vitamin D3 vitamin K2
vitamin A
uh Basic Essentials you know some amino
acids if you're eating uh Quality Meats
you should get sufficient proteins and
amino acids but uh some of the other
aminos like El citrine if you're someone
that exercises really helps and you know
El citrine helps with erectile function
for men as well being a a good Vaso
dilator and John asks are there any
downsides to taking vitamin K2 yes you
it's contraindicated in patients on
Kadin um because it does negate the
anti- coagulative effect of of the
medication so if you've had if you have
apib or if you've had Sten you know
check with your your healthc care
provider who prescribed you your blood
thinners if K2 is contraindicated before
you take it
[Music]